<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Windows10 on  [_]3</title>
    <link>http://www.mindginative.com/tags/windows10/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Windows10 on  [_]3</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Copyright notice</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 May 2017 16:06:19 +1200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://www.mindginative.com/tags/windows10/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>First Taste of Win10 BitLocker</title>
      <link>http://www.mindginative.com/posts/first-taste-of-win10-bitlocker/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 May 2017 16:06:19 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.mindginative.com/posts/first-taste-of-win10-bitlocker/</guid>
      <description>I bought the idea of encrypting my OS drive, since I&amp;rsquo;m on Windows 10 I opted the closed source utility called BitLocker. Prior to trusting my gut - I had initially configured my Ubuntu-based headless server with eCryptfs.
If you peek at eCryptfs about page, one of the authors became a member of BitLocker team at Microsoft - so I guess that&amp;rsquo;s why I pushed the &amp;ldquo;OK&amp;rdquo; button.
The Famous bcmwl63a.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NodeJS Development Inside Docker on Windows 10</title>
      <link>http://www.mindginative.com/posts/nodejs-development-inside-docker-with-windows10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2017 16:39:23 +1300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.mindginative.com/posts/nodejs-development-inside-docker-with-windows10/</guid>
      <description>Wait, what ? Moving to Windows10 (6 months ago as of this writing) as my main OS is a bit hard, just a little bit. I use commandline ALL THE TIME and I can&amp;rsquo;t live without the developer&amp;rsquo;s Swiss army knife on my side - tiny tools that make our life easier: grep, sed, ps, tree, ssh, find &amp;hellip;
&amp;ldquo;Bash On Windows&amp;rdquo; was a good strategy from Microsoft - I didn&amp;rsquo;t bother about switching to Windows and I didn&amp;rsquo;t think twice, I was more worried about which machine to buy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Install FFmpeg from source on Ubuntu Bash on Win10</title>
      <link>http://www.mindginative.com/posts/install-ffmpeg-from-source-ubuntu-win10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2016 01:17:35 +1300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.mindginative.com/posts/install-ffmpeg-from-source-ubuntu-win10/</guid>
      <description>I was working on transcoding videos into different formats, resolutions so it could be played on various desktops, tablets and mobile devices. My main working machine is Dell XPS13 on Windows 10 with Ubuntu Bash enabled, some of my needed libraries is missing and needs recompilation of FFmpeg the one that came from Ubuntu 14.04 repo.
I think I&amp;rsquo;ve literraly spent hours or probably days buildin/re-building libraries just to get the videos transcoded into my desired format.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Go1.7 installation via GVM on Ubuntu Bash on Windows 10</title>
      <link>http://www.mindginative.com/posts/go1-7-bash-on-win10/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Nov 2016 22:27:10 +1300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.mindginative.com/posts/go1-7-bash-on-win10/</guid>
      <description>Since moving to Hugo few months ago my installation history with Go was quick and dirty, I just want to get something up running to get started with Hugo. 48 hours ago I was playing with Go, I thought of building a simple cli utility where CI server can hook in and start building something - of course it has be built on top of Go, enough to get my around its dev-ecosystem.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>